Welcome, after last lecture, now we have a working control rig for snapping both of our
欢迎，经过上次的讲座，现在我们有了一个有效的控制装置，可以在攀爬时将我们的双手和双脚都扣在
hands and feet to the climbable surface when we are climbing.
手和脚在可攀爬的表面上。
And starting from this lecture, we'll look at how we can use motion morphing to take
从这节课开始，我们将研究如何使用运动变形技术来进一步提高
our climbing system further.
我们的攀爬系统更进一步。
So what is motion morphing?
那么什么是运动变形呢？
Well in simple terms, it's a feature that can dynamically adjust our character's root
简单地说，它是一个可以动态地调整我们的角色的根部运动的功能
motion to align to the targets that we specify.
来对准我们指定的目标。
So far we have used root motion to help us to achieve things like climbing down the ledge,
到目前为止，我们已经使用了根部运动来帮助我们实现诸如爬下壁架的事情、
climbing up the ledge, and thanks to the control rig, we can manually adjust how much we want
由于控制装置的存在，我们可以手动调整我们想要的根部运动的程度。
the root motion to move our character.
根部运动来移动我们的角色。
But still, the value there is predefined inside of the editor and there's no control of it
但是，那里的值仍然是在编辑器中预定义的，而且在运行时也无法控制它
during runtime.
在运行期间。
And if without control rig, there really isn't an editor solution for us to adjust the movement
如果没有控制设备，就真的没有一个编辑器可以让我们调整根部运动的移动
of the root motion animation inside of the editor.
根部运动动画在编辑器中的移动。
But everything changes with motion morphing.
但是有了运动变形，一切都变了。
So with motion morphing, we can dynamically set the target for the root motion animation
所以有了运动变形，我们可以动态地设置根部运动动画的目标
and in the runtime, we can warp our character to the target.
并且在运行时，我们可以将我们的角色扭曲到目标上。
And this is such a powerful feature that can allow us to move and rotate our character
这是一个非常强大的功能，可以让我们移动和旋转我们的角色
so the movement of it fits better with the animation.
这样它的运动就能更好地配合动画。
So let's look at how we can set it up.
因此，让我们来看看我们如何设置它。
First we'll need to enable the motion morphing plugin for our project.
首先，我们需要为我们的项目启用运动变形插件。
I'm going to go to edit and inside the plugins in here, I'm going to search for motion morphing.
我要去编辑，在这里的插件里面，我要搜索运动变形。
So this is the plugin that we need to enable.
所以这是我们需要启用的插件。
Take it and just click yes for this message and we'll need to restart our editor.
拿到它，然后点击这个信息的 "是"，我们就需要重新启动我们的编辑器。
So I'm going to click restart now.
所以我现在要点击重新启动。
All right after having the editor back, I'm going to close this tab and close my project.
好了，在编辑器恢复后，我将关闭这个标签并关闭我的项目。
Next I'm going to create a motion morphing component inside of our character class.
接下来我将在我们的角色类中创建一个运动变形组件。
So I'm going to scroll down and open this system character.h.
所以我要向下滚动并打开这个系统character.h。
First I'm going to forward declare the type.
首先，我要向前声明这个类型。
So the type is going to be class HueMotionMorphingComponent.
所以这个类型将是HueMotionMorphingComponent类。
Then I'm going to declare a member variable for it.
然后我将为它声明一个成员变量。
So copy this type, go down.
所以复制这个类型，往下看。
I'm going to place it in here.
我将把它放在这里。
Copy this Hue property.
复制这个Hue属性。
Place it in here and I'm going to name this variable MotionMorphingComponent.
把它放在这里，我将把这个变量命名为MotionMorphingComponent。
And next thing I'm going to head over to the constructor to create a default sub object.
接下来，我要到构造器那里去创建一个默认的子对象。
So press Ctrl + K, Ctrl + O to go to the cpp file.
所以按Ctrl + K, Ctrl + O转到cpp文件。
Then I'm going to copy this name and scroll down.
然后我将复制这个名字并向下滚动。
I'm going to delete these two lines of comment and place the variable in here.
我要删除这两行注释，把变量放在这里。
And I'm going to copy this create default sub object.
我将复制这个创建默认子对象。
The type is going to be HueMotionMorphingComponent.
类型将是HueMotionMorphingComponent。
And the name, I'm going to call it MotionMorphingComp.
名字，我打算叫它MotionMorphingComp。
And we'll also need to include the header file for this motion morphing.
我们还需要包括这个运动变形的头文件。
And the fastest way to find that is to select this type and press F12 to go to its header
找到它的最快方法是选择这个类型，然后按F12键进入它的头文件。
file.
文件。
Then press Ctrl + K, Ctrl + O. I'm going to select this header file, go back to my
然后按Ctrl + K, Ctrl + O。我将选择这个头文件，回到我的
cpp and paste it in here.
cpp并把它粘贴到这里。
Alright I'm going to try to compile and I don't have a successful compile.
好了，我要尝试编译了，我没有编译成功。
Let's investigate the reason.
让我们调查一下原因。
So scroll down.
所以向下滚动。
Here you can see it says cannot open this include file MotionMorphingComponent.h.
在这里你可以看到它说不能打开这个包含文件MotionMorphingComponent.h。
And in here I have some red squiggles.
在这里我有一些红色的斜线。
So if this happens, usually it means there's a missing module that we need to include inside
所以如果发生这种情况，通常意味着我们需要在build.cs文件中包含一个缺失的模块。
of our build.cs file.
我们的build.cs文件中。
And to quickly find out which module that we need to include, the fastest way will be
为了快速找出我们需要加入的模块，最快的方法是
searching for this header file.
搜索这个头文件。
So I'm going to copy this name, paste it in here.
所以我要复制这个名字，把它粘贴到这里。
And you can see this header file is under the module MotionMorphing.
你可以看到这个头文件在MotionMorphing模块下。
So I'm going to select this folder, press F2.
所以我将选择这个文件夹，按F2键。
Once I have the name selected, I'm going to press Ctrl + C to copy it.
一旦我选择了这个名字，我就要按Ctrl + C来复制它。
Then I'm going to go back to my build.cs.
然后我再回到我的build.cs。
So scroll down and double click to open this ClimbSystem.build.cs.
所以向下滚动并双击，打开这个CimbSystem.build.cs。
And we'll need that module in here.
我们将需要这个模块在这里。
So I'm going to start this one on a new line and organize these names.
所以我要在新的一行开始这个模块，并组织这些名称。
So these are the existing modules that we've already included.
所以这些是我们已经包含的现有模块。
And I'm going to add in a new one.
我将添加一个新的模块。
So the next one that we need to add in is this MotionMorphing.
所以我们需要添加的下一个模块是MotionMorphing。
Alright I'm going to try to compile again.
好吧，我再试着编译一下。
And this time I have a successful compile.
这一次，我的编译成功了。
And now if I go back to my character.cpp, you can see that Red Squiggle is still there.
现在如果我回到我的character.cpp，你可以看到Red Squiggle还在那里。
And if we don't get rid of this later, when we need to access this variable, we won't
如果我们以后不把它去掉，当我们需要访问这个变量时，我们就不能自动完成。
be able to have auto completion back.
我们就不能再有自动完成的功能了。
And the fastest way to do that, I'm going to launch my editor back first.
做到这一点的最快方法是，我先启动我的编辑器。
So inside of my editor, I'm going to go to Tools and I'm going to click this Refresh
因此，在我的编辑器中，我将进入 "工具"，点击 "刷新"。
Visual Studio Project.
Visual Studio项目。
Alright the refreshing is complete.
好了，刷新完成了。
Now I'm going to close my project again and go back to Visual Studio.
现在我将再次关闭我的项目，回到Visual Studio。
Now I can click this Reload All.
现在我可以点击这个Reload All。
And you can see after reloading that Red Squiggle is gone.
你可以看到重新加载后，红色斜线已经消失了。
And now we should be able to have the auto completion back.
现在我们应该可以恢复自动完成的功能了。
Alright I'm going to close this build.cs file.
好了，我要关闭这个build.cs文件。
And there's one more thing that I want to do inside of code.
还有一件事我想在代码中做。
So go back to the header file.
所以请回到头文件中。
I'm first going to copy this type.
我首先要复制这个类型。
Then go to the bottom of it.
然后转到它的底部。
So I'm going to create a getter for that component.
所以我要为这个组件创建一个getter。
So start a new line.
所以开始一个新的行。
It's going to be another force inline.
这将是另一个内联力。
And this is the type.
这是该类型。
I'm going to call this getMotionMorphingComponent.
我将把它叫做getMotionMorphingComponent。
And it's going to be const.
它将是常数。
And I'm going to return this motion morphing component.
我将会返回这个运动变形组件。
Alright I'm going to compile again.
好了，我要再次编译了。
I have a successful compile.
我已经编译成功了。
I'm going to launch my editor back.
我将重新启动我的编辑器。
Go inside of my editor.
进入我的编辑器。
I'm going to double click to open this character blueprint.
我将双击来打开这个角色蓝图。
And you can see in here we have one more component added and it's this motion morphing component.
你可以看到在这里我们又添加了一个组件，它就是这个运动变形组件。
And that's the basic set for motion morphing.
这就是运动变形的基本设置。
And there's one last thing that I want to do.
还有最后一件事我想做。
So I'm going to close this window.
所以我将关闭这个窗口。
And in the resources dropdown of this lecture, you should be able to find a USF file.
在本讲座的资源下拉菜单中，你应该能够找到一个USF文件。
It's the animation that we're going to use later.
这是我们以后要使用的动画。
Make sure you download it before you proceed.
在你继续之前，确保你下载它。
I've already done that.
我已经这样做了。
So the file is called voting_rm.
所以这个文件叫做 voting_rm。
So I'm going to select this file.
所以我将选择这个文件。
Control + C to copy it.
Control + C来复制它。
Go inside of my clamping system.
进入我的钳制系统内部。
Double click to open this content folder.
双击来打开这个内容文件夹。
And Control + V to paste the USF in here.
然后Control + V将USF粘贴到这里。
Then go back to my project.
然后回到我的项目。
Go inside of the content folder.
转到内容文件夹里面。
And this is the animation that we're going to use.
这就是我们要使用的动画。
And we'll need to assign it a new skeleton.
我们需要给它分配一个新的骨架。
So right mouse button click and select this replace skeleton.
所以鼠标右键单击并选择这个替换骨架。
So this is an animation that comes from one of Epic's sample project.
所以这是一个来自Epic的样本项目的动画。
I've already retargeted it to be compatible with our SK mannequin.
我已经对它进行了重定位，以便与我们的SK人体模型兼容。
So just select this skeleton and click OK.
所以只要选择这个骨架并点击OK。
And now the animation should be ready.
现在这个动画应该已经准备好了。
Double click to open it.
双击来打开它。
And you can see this is a voting animation.
你可以看到这是个投票动画。
And if I select the root bone here, it also has the root motion intact.
如果我选择这里的根骨，它也有完整的根部动作。
And later we'll look at how we can use this animation with motion morphing.
稍后我们将看看我们如何使用这个动画和运动变形。
It's time for our challenge today.
现在是我们今天的挑战时间。
The challenge is I'd like you to enable the motion morphing plugin in your project.
这个挑战是我希望你在你的项目中启用运动变形插件。
After this step, same as I did, I'd like you to create a motion morphing component for
在这一步之后，和我一样，我希望你为你的角色创建一个运动变形组件。
your character.
你的角色。
And don't forget to include the corresponding header file.
不要忘记包含相应的头文件。
And also you'll need to add in the corresponding module to your build.cs file.
而且你还需要在你的build.cs文件中加入相应的模块。
And once you have the component ready, last thing, make sure you import the animation
一旦你准备好组件，最后一件事，确保你导入动画
for voting.
用于投票。
Alright, pause the video now and give this a go.
好了，现在暂停视频，给它一个机会。
Or refer back to the video if you need help.
如果你需要帮助，也可以参考视频。
And I'll see you in the next lecture.
我们在下一个讲座中再见吧。
[music]
[音乐]